이 문제를 자주 exploding gradient나
These problems are often
called the exploding and
vanishing gradient라고 합니다.
vanishing gradient problems.
놀랍게도 매우 다른 방법들로
이 문제를 해결합니다.
And we're going to fix them,
surprisingly in very different ways.
하나는 매우 단순한 hack을 사용하고
다른 하나는 매우 우아한 방법을 사용합니다.
One using a very simple hack, and
the other one with a very elegant but
그러나, 약간 모델이 복잡해집니다.
slightly complicated
change to the model.
단순한 hack은 gradient clipping 라고 합니다.
The simple hack is called
gradient clipping.
gradients가 끝없이 커지는 것을
방지하기 위해서
In order to prevent the gradients
from growing inbounded,
gradients의 norm을 계산하고
그 rorm이 너무 커지면, 각 단계에서 수축시킵니다.
you can compute their norm and shrink
their step, when the norm grows too big.
이것을 편법스럽지만
It's hacky, but 간단하고 효율적입니다.
it's cheap and effective.
gradient vanishing은 매우
다른 방법으로 해결합니다.
The more difficult thing to
fix is gradient vanishing.
Vanishing gradients가 단지 최근의 사건만
기억하도록 모델을 만들어주고
Vanishing gradients make your model
only remember recent events and
많이 떨어진 과거는 기억하지 않습니다.
forget the more distant past,
recurrent neural nets은 몇 시점을 지난
과거는 잘 작동하지 않는다는 경향을 의미합니다.
which means recurrent neural nets tend
to not work well past a few time steps.